[
  {
    "question": "________ ________ is any part of a strata plan that is not part of a strata lot.",
    "answer": "<strong>Common property</strong> is any part of a strata plan that is not part of a strata lot."
  },
  {
    "question": "A subdivision of land, as opposed to a building, into separate parcels creates a _____ ______ strata development.",
    "answer": "A subdivision of land, as opposed to a building, into separate parcels creates a <strong>bare land</strong> strata development."
  },
  {
    "question": "A strata lot's contribution to common expenses is determined by the schedule of _____ ______.",
    "answer": "A strata lot's contribution to common expenses is determined by the schedule of <strong>unit entitlement</strong>."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Strata Property Act does not apply to strata developments with fewer than five strata lots.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "The Strata Property Act does not apply to strata developments with fewer than five strata lots.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) False</strong><br />The Strata Property Act applies to all stratified lots in BC, irrespective of the number of strata lots in the strata plan."
  },
  {
    "question": "A strata development must maintain a _______ ______ _____ for expenses that occur less often than once a year or that do not usually occur.",
    "answer": "A strata development must maintain a <strong>contingency reserve fund</strong> for expenses that occur less often than once a year or that do not usually occur."
  },
  {
    "question": "If a rule passed by a strata council conflicts with one of the strata's bylaws, which prevails?<br />&nbsp;(1) The bylaw<br />&nbsp;(2) The rule",
    "answer": "If a rule passed by a strata council conflicts with one of the strata's bylaws, which prevails?<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) The bylaw</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) The rule"
  },
  {
    "question": "Generally speaking, how often must the owners of a strata development elect a new strata council?",
    "answer": "Every year."
  },
  {
    "question": "Common property designated for the exclusive use of the owners of one or more strata lots is called ________ common property.",
    "answer": "Common property designated for the exclusive use of the owners of one or more strata lots is called <strong>limited</strong> common property."
  },
  {
    "question": "Unit entitlement is generally calculated based on the _______ _______ of each strata lot.",
    "answer": "Unit entitlement is generally calculated based on the <strong>habitable area</strong> of each strata lot."
  },
  {
    "question": "All individuals on a strata council will be held to the same statutory requirements, regardless of their relative expertise.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "All individuals on a strata council will be held to the same statutory requirements, regardless of their relative expertise.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) True</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) False"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a <strong>subdivision</strong>?",
    "answer": "A subdivision is the division of land into two or more parcels."
  },
  {
    "question": "The____ _____ is created by the owner developer and governs the finances of the strata corporation until the first annual general meeting.",
    "answer": "The <strong>interim budget</strong> is created by the owner developer and governs the finances of the strata corporation until the first annual general meeting."
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe short term exclusive use.",
    "answer": "Short term exclusive use is a special privilege granted to owners and tenants to exclusively use common property that is not designated limited common property."
  },
  {
    "question": "A strata lot owner’s _______ _________ sets out their proportionate ownership in the common property and the strata expenses and liabilities for which the owner is responsible.",
    "answer": "A strata lot owner’s <strong>unit entitlement</strong> sets out their proportionate ownership in the common property and the strata expenses and liabilities for which the owner is responsible."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which documents inform a strata lot purchaser whether there is any money owing to the strata corporation in respect of that strata lot?",
    "answer": "A Certificate of Payment and an Information Certificate"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a depreciation report?",
    "answer": "A depreciation report is an estimation of the repair and replacement cost for major items owned by the strata corporation and the expected life of those items."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the case of a leasehold strata lot, the developer is the \"leasehold landlord\".<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "In the case of a leasehold strata lot, the developer is the \"leasehold landlord\".<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) False</strong><br />The developer is the \"leasehold tenant\" and can sell the leasehold interest to interested buyers."
  },
  {
    "question": "At the expiry of a strata lot lease, the leasehold landlord may elect to convert each strata lot to freehold on a case-by-case basis.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "At the expiry of a strata lot lease, the leasehold landlord may elect to convert each strata lot to freehold on a case-by-case basis.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) False</strong><br />At the expiry of the strata lot lease, the leasehold landlord can convert the project to freehold only if they transfers fee simple title to all of the strata lots to their respective leasehold tenants."
  }
]